<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Everything Technical</title><link href="http://everytech.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://everytech.org/feeds/adobe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://everytech.org/</id><updated>2014-03-11T18:59:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Adobe AEM/CQ Content Authoring Trainging</title><link href="http://everytech.org/adobe-aemcq-content-authoring-trainging.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T18:59:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joshua H</name></author><id>tag:everytech.org,2014-03-11:adobe-aemcq-content-authoring-trainging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just went through the one day training for the authoring of content on
Adobe's AEM/CQ software. The class was alright, I learned a few things.
Every class I take I understand a bit more about how it will integrate
into our setting. The unfortunate thing is I still don't see the big
picture. On the subject of the class if you don't know anything about
AEM/CQ it will definitely inform you and teach you all about the
authoring side of it. I would suggest it for those who have not touched
AEM/CQ before for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I now have a monitoring system set up for my web server and
also analytic software set up to help track visitors. I don't plan on a
lot of visitors but the project itself still is pretty nifty. I am still
working on what I'm going to do for a logo and maybe more customizing of
the site. For now I will hopefully be able to start posting more!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Adobe"></category><category term="AEM"></category><category term="CMS"></category><category term="Content Author"></category><category term="CQ"></category><category term="Server"></category><category term="Software"></category><category term="Training"></category></entry><entry><title>Adobe AEM/CQ System Administration Training</title><link href="http://everytech.org/adobe-aemcq-system-administration-training.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-03T20:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Joshua H</name></author><id>tag:everytech.org,2014-03-03:adobe-aemcq-system-administration-training.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just got back from my adobe training in McLean Virgina. The class was
very interesting and while I did have to leave early, it was still very
worth the trip. The documentation which came in the form of a hard to
read PDF (low DPI) is the most important part. The instructor was great
but you can’t take him with you. Not going to get too in depth about the
class now as I hope to complete more of my blog. I hope to be making it
a little more secure and adding in a few more pieces and parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Admin"></category><category term="Adobe"></category><category term="AEM"></category><category term="CQ"></category><category term="PDF"></category><category term="System Administrator"></category><category term="Training"></category></entry></feed>