<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Everything Technical</title><link href="http://everytech.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://everytech.org/feeds/os-x.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://everytech.org/</id><updated>2014-04-19T19:11:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Apple's SMC and New HDDs</title><link href="http://everytech.org/apples-smc-and-new-hdds.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-19T19:11:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joshua H</name></author><id>tag:everytech.org,2014-04-19:apples-smc-and-new-hdds.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was just asked by a long time friend what software I recommended him
to install on his fairly new iMac to control the fan speed. As many iMac
owners know after swapping out your hard drive for a fancy solid state
drive or just replacing your bad hard drive with one off the shelf, some
new problems occur. Apple has installed hard drives with proprietary
temperature sensors in them and when you replace that drive with one not
compatible your fan picks up to take off speeds. Super loud and annoy,
just for replacing your hard drive or upgrading to a SSD. Apple's SMC,
system management controller, monitors sensors in your iMac and adjusts
certain devices based on the input it gets. Thus a hard drive not
reporting, which reads as a very hot hard drive to the SMC, means crank
the fans up! The simplest solution without opening the machine back up
is to install a small application that allows you to control the fan
speed. Best yet the software I recommend is free and can read SMART data
to help monitor hard drive temperatures without the need of a
proprietary sensor. There are a couple other suitable options out there
but from my research and testing this was my favorite and the one I
suggest to my friends. Give it a try, if you like it consider donating
to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://exirion.net/ssdfanctrl/"&gt; SSD Fan Control - SMC Fan Control
Replacement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Apple"></category><category term="Hard Drive"></category><category term="Proprietary"></category></entry></feed>