<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Everything Technical</title><link href="http://everytech.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://everytech.org/feeds/windows.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://everytech.org/</id><updated>2014-04-11T21:09:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Windows Password Removal</title><link href="http://everytech.org/windows-password-removal-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-11T21:09:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Joshua H</name></author><id>tag:everytech.org,2014-04-11:windows-password-removal-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sticking with the topic of Microsoft Windows, I have an update on
password removals. One of Mark and I's problems we had just before we
left our last place of employment was trying to reset the password on a
windows 8 machine. At the time windows 8 came out the options for
removing a password were log into the Microsoft account that the
computer was set up with or be super sad. Turns out a lot people were
super sad. Well good news for everyone, the main tool we used to remove
a password has been updated to work with windows 8! Our favorite way to
use this software is PXE network booting or installed on a USB drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Check it out.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pogostick.net/~pnh/ntpasswd/"&gt;Offline NT Password &amp;amp; Registry
Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Bootdisk"></category><category term="Offline"></category><category term="Password"></category></entry><entry><title>Windows 8.1 and eDrive SSDs</title><link href="http://everytech.org/windows-8-1-and-edrive-ssds.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-05T21:55:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mark P</name></author><id>tag:everytech.org,2014-04-05:windows-8-1-and-edrive-ssds.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I built someone a computer this week, a pretty basic system with
Windows 8.1 and a Samsung 840 EVO SSD. I had some vague recollection of
a conversation Josh and I had about encryption being enabled by default,
so I decided to look into that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's Microsoft's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn306081.aspx"&gt;blurb&lt;/a&gt; on
the subject. Basically, on a clean Windows 8.1 install on a system with
a TPM, Secure Boot, UEFI, Connected Standby support, and an eDrive
compliant ssd, and probably some other requirements - Windows will
automatically enable hardware-based Bitlocker device encryption and
upload a recovery key to an associated Microsoft account. You can toggle
this protection on or off on supported systems on the PC Settings\ PC
Info metro app. Seems to be a pretty cool feature. Seamless and fast
security in the event a computer is lost or stolen, although I can see
it becoming a problem for anyone who has to support end users, do data
recovery, etc., especially as systems supporting this feature become
more prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, cool. What's not cool is that Windows 8.1 will, during setup,
automatically provision a compatible drive for eDrive without user
interaction, thereby locking out the ability to issue ATA security
commands to the drive (set ATA passwords, perform secure erase), which
sort of sucks, because on many SSDs this is practically irreversible.
For most users, this probably won't be too big of a deal, but it might
matter for people who want to repurpose or sell the drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is supposed to be a method of resetting the drive back to its
factory state by using the PSID number printed on the drive, but most
manufactures do not provide a utility to do this. It's a pretty awesome
feature, too. Just enter a code and the drive is instantly and securely
wiped. As near as I could tell, only Seagate has a tool to do this.
Samsung and Crucial don't provide a tool. On their forums, Crucial has
users RMAing drives to get around this. Samsung refers customers to
Microsoft, who in turn refers them back to Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eDrive seems like a worthwhile feature, but MS and SSD manufacturers
sort of jumped the gun on implementing it without properly documenting
and supporting it. I'd like to mess with it once the process is a little
more mature, but for the time being, I decided to sidestep the feature
by adding a registry key during install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Policies\Microsoft\Windows\EnhancedStorageDevices]
"TCGSecurityActivationDisabled"=dword:00000001
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Bitlocker"></category><category term="eDrive"></category><category term="Encryption"></category><category term="Samsung"></category><category term="SSD"></category><category term="UEFI"></category></entry></feed>